in this video we will dive into one of the most fundamental link list techniques how to reverse a link list in
place without using any extra space after knowing this technique you will be able to solve a variety of lead code
problems that require reversing a link list or even just a portion of it I will also share additional lead code problems
you can practice to become an expert at reversing a link list so let&#39;s get into it let&#39;s walk through a classic lead
code problem to see this in action just a quick note if at any point you feel like pausing the video and trying the
problem yourself feel free to do so lead code 206 reverse link list you are given the head of a singly link list and your
task is to reverse the list in place for example if the input list is this output would look like this reversing the list
means flipping the direction of each pointer so that every node points to its previous node instead of the next an I
approach will be to copy the values of the link list into an array reverse the array and then iterate to update the list but this approach requires order of
an extra space where n is the size of the list and it isn&#39;t efficient instead we can reverse the list in order of n
time and Order of one space using three pointers previous current and next it start with the previous pointer as none
since there is no previous node at the beginning current pointer points to the head of the list and the next pointer
helps us temporarily store the next node in the list so we don&#39;t lose track while reversing in each iteration save the
next node in the next pointer by setting next to current do next reverse the length at the current node by setting
current do next to previous move previous pointer to current as we have finished processing this node and move
the current pointer to next to process the next node we repeat this process until we have reversed the entire list once current becomes none which means we
have reached the end of the list previous will point to the new head of the revers list using this approach we reverse the list in place without using
any extra memory other than the threep pointers the time complexity is order of n where n is the number of nodes in the
link list the space complexity is order of one since we only use a few pointers and don&#39;t allocate any extra space for
ReStore in the list here is how it looks like in code here I&#39;m using Java but you can find code for other popular programming languages in my GitHub
repository code or some lead code resources link is in the description it start by initializing previous tunel and
current to the head of the link list it create through the list while current is not null which means until we reach the
end of the list save the next node by setting next to current next reverse the current notes pointer by setting
current. next to previous and move previous to current and current to next for the next iteration once the loop
finishes previous will point to the new head of the reverse list so return it there are some more lead code problems
you can practice using this approach you can find these problems on algo master. simply head to the practice space search
for this pattern or use the filter drop down and start practicing on this platform you can Mark problems as complete or start them for later
revision you can also find the links to get YouTube solutions for each problem if you want to check out the full lead code patterns playlist click here don&#39;t
forget to like subscribe and hit the Bell icon so you won&#39;t miss my future videos thanks for watching and I will see you in the next one